WILLIAM WHYTE

https://wwhyte01.github.io/digital-cv/

https://uk.linkedin.com/in/william-whyte-ni

Software engineer with 4 years' experience in an Agile environment. Experience in creating & delivering applications throughout their lifecycle. Always keen to support & maintain ownership of applications by providing production support and QA when required. Interested in security engineering and completed a PGCert in Cybersecurity in my spare time.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Reward Insight

May 2023 - Present

Full stack engineer delivering banking applications. Responsibilities include:

- Worked on data migration project for banks data stored from a legacy database into new AWS database.
- Ensured system can deal with large volumes of data through performance testing.
- Safeguarded processing of PCI data implemented through tokenization in AWS.
- Worked with AWS lambdas and fargate, implemented in .NET and Node JS.
- Refining, prioritizing and tasking user stories for the team backlog based on customer feedback from sprint reviews.
- Handover applications to production support ensuring the project is fully documented and contains necessary AWS alerting and logs.
- Delivered items by working independently and through pair-programming for more complex features.
- Deployment of code throughout environments in each sprint using Jenkins.

Technologies used: AWS, C#, Git, Jenkins .NET, Node JS, Postman, Serverless, SQL

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - Aflac NI

Jan 2020 - April 2023

Pega developer for US health insurance applications. Responsibilities include:

- Early architecture of projects after analysis of the manual business processes, becoming a SME for the team on how the business/customer operates along with what we need to deliver.
- Developed key functionality along with incorporating non-functional requirements, namely security and usability.
- Worked closely with AppSec; through threat modelling identified application's assets to concentrate on what risks to highlight by applying mitigation controls.
- Overlooked deployment of code throughout environments in each sprint using CI/CD DevOps pipeline.
- Automation of user stories, writing robust unit tests along with UI tests in testing environment.
- Reading log files and debugging when production support is needed.
- Training and mentoring new team members.
- Building relationships with key stakeholders along with presenting and demoing application functionality to them; namely in sprint reviews or when US stakeholders visit the NI office.

Technologies used: Git, Pega, Pega CI/CD Pipelines, Power BI, Python, Robot Framework, Selenium

Education

Queen's University, Belfast

Applied Cybersecurity PGCert with Commendation (66)

2021-2022

Technologies used: Burp Suite, C++, Kali Linux, Wireshark

Software Development MSc with Commendation (61)

2018-2019

Technologies used: CSS, HTML, Java, JavaScript, PHP, SQL

History BA Honours (2.1)

2012-2015

IT Certifications

ISTQB - Foundations of Software Testing

2020

Pega - Certified System Architect, Certified Senior System Architect

2020, 2021

Additional Info

- 8 years working in various customer facing roles. Required a strong grasp of excellent customer satisfaction and dealing with members of public of all ages. Effectively time managed when delegating duties to team members.
- Passionate about Environmental, Social & Governance (ESG) and became a major role in Aflac NI's 'Green Team' the team obtained the company the Responsible Plastic Management (RPM) certification.
- Interested in reading and learning history; awarded QUB's Certificate in Entrepreneurship Studies and QUB's Mary Gardiner Prize Award (highest distinction in ancient history modules)